

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







IT Analyst seeking roles in System Analysis, Project Management, Configuration Management, System Installation, Client Management, Software Troubleshooting, IT Infrastructure Support, Requirement Gathering, Technical Architecture, VMWare, Azure



Current Designation: IT Analyst Total Experience: 9 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Tata Consultancy Services Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Hyderabad, Dubai, Singapore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: System Analyst

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: IT Analyst, System Analyst, System Analysis, Project Management, Configuration Management, System Installation, Client Management, Software Troubleshooting, IT Infrastructure Support, Requirement Gathering, Technical

Architecture, VMW are, Azure

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Currently working with TCS on Mcrosoft Project as a L3/L4 resource on Intune and SCCM Technology. Having total of 9 years of overall experience on different technologies like Intune, SCCM, VMware, Application Packaging..

Administering / Supporting around 350K SCCM and 400K Intune Mcrosoft Enterprise Devices:

1 Central site - 4 primary sites. One of the largest SCCMenvironments with always latest update of SSCMand Intune version working with Intune/SCCMDev team directly. The first largest production environment where SCCMDev team applying the new upgrade version.

Currently working on a Project with regular Administration of Current Branch Infrastructure with its components like Software Update Management and Application Management, Installation & Re-installation of SCCM client with related Troubleshooting

Experience in Android work profile migration project.

Work Experience

Tata Consultancy Services as IT Analyst Feb 2018 to Till Date

EUC- SCCM and Mobile device Management project:

Managing a Global SCCMsite which consist of 01 Central site, 05primary sites, in each region to support overall 3.5K SCCM clients and 400K mobile devices.

devices with a team size of 30+ SCCM SME (Onsite + Offshore) to take care of infrastructure. support of these servers i.e. security updates, OS upgrades, SQL upgrades and day to day health monitoring. Managing End user computing services i.e. Application Deployment, Patch management, SCCM Client health and Mobile devices management through Intune and accountable for overall operations for these services areas.

Key Responsibilities:

Intune Administrator - Level4

Support Premiere Mcrosoft customers in the Implementation of Intune/Azure mobile device management with SCCM and Office 365/Exchange hybrid environments.

Develop, deploy and manage mobile applications and mobile application management policies with Azure including

Team Technical lead responsible for the resolution of complex issues, quality, escalations, KB submission and documentation, and continued training of a team of 20 engineers.

Subject matter expert for Apple iOS APN certificates as well as the Apple device enrollment program (DEP). communicate with high priority enterprise businesses regarding the status of support incidents in critical situations. Assisting end users with troubleshooting of device performance issues

Analyzing the issues and providing the fix, Creating documentation and providing KB's to Lower level teams.

Administer and Configure mobile devices for enterprise users

Working knowledge of Powershell, Exchange Active Sync, SCEP and NDES certificates, and some Power BI

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

SCCM Infra Support:

Installation of ConfigMgr Central Administration Site, Primary Site and Secondary Site and others site system roles Depth knowledge on Site system roles and its components

Administration Mcrosoft SCCM2012 environment to latest, including creating or editing security groups, application deployments (collections, and PowerShell scripts), patch management, general troubles nooting, log analysis.

Knowledge of Software Distribution in three tier hierarchy.

Troubleshoot and resolve SCCM management point policy issues and package/program deployment failures.

Troubleshooting ConfigMgr SQL Replication issues

Troubleshooting end to end MP communication issues.

Installing SCCM clients with Client-Push and manual installing

Troubleshooting the package replication all over the environment.

Periodical health checks of SCCM environment and site backup.

Provide operational support and troubleshooting of system infrastructures.

Creating Standard Documents and Uploading into Shared Wiki for projects which can help other team members to resolve issue efficiently and quickly.

Attending daily handoffs meeting to sync with the onsite team.

Checking Configuration Manager site system inboxes for backlogs

Instrumental in monitoring the Site Services & Database Servers daily across pre-defined Checklist.

Provide weekly monthly reports on Incident, change management and bugs and overall performance of team,

attending and present meeting along with team leads with customer on Configuration Management infrastructure.

Participating in system build, upgrade, deployments, and patch management.

Responsible for L1/L2 level of technical support all servers related issues.

SCCM Application and Packaging Deployment:

Gathering the client requirement based on that proceeding with Packaging Model or Application Model.

Software Distribution Application/Package creation in SCCM

Packaging and testing it to testing machine.

Performing quality Check (QC).

Distributing and deploying the packages.

Working on collection Creation, Package distribution and Production deployment.

SCCM Patching Management:

Performing Pre QC-before patching

Infosys Technologies as SCCM Administrator

Mar 2017 to Feb 2018

- SCCM Apps/Package creation and deployment
- SCCM Infrastructure support Worked on Silent Deployment of various Applications using Microsoft Installer (MSI)
- Worked with SCCM 2012 to create collections, packages, deployments and deployed software packages.
- Installation of SCCMagent Through Client Push method and troubleshooting Client Agent issues.
- SCCM Apps/Packages troubleshooting
- Deployed Patches to over 6000 client machines on Monthly basis
- Troubleshooting Patche failures in servers and client machines
- Hands of Experience on troubleshooting Database replication issues.
- Monitoring MP/Primary backlogs
- Supported over 10K enrolled devices in an Hybrid Environment.
- Hands on Experience on IOS/Android/Windows Enrollment issues.
- End user support to Users on how to enrol their devices in Intune using Company Portal
- Troubleshooted Device compliance policies
- Conditional access support
- Good Knowledge on Intune life cycle
- Deploying apps in Intune Hybrid Environment
- Good knowledge on SCCMOSD process.
- Good knowledge on USMT
- Worked on Bitlocker Administration

Broadridge Financial Solutions as Process Lead

Aug 2010 to Jun 2016

- Installation of SCCM agent Through Client Push method and troubleshooting Client Agent issues.
- Monitor Client health issues and taking actions accordingly
- Hands on experience on Deploying Apps/Packages
- Hands on experience on troubleshooting Packages/Application deployment failures on client machines.
- Deploying Monthly patches to 10,000 client machines and troubleshooting using SCCMlogs
- Analysing and applying patches, service packs, and infrastructure updates.
- Hands on Experience on creating Upgrade and Refresh OSD task sequences
- OS deployment troubleshooting
- Good knowledge on converting EXE's to MSI
- Created templates from VMs and deploy VMs from templates, ISO images.
- Created and managing virtual machines and installing VMTools into VMs.
- Performed Snapshots, Cloning, Migrations

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Nizam College, Hyderabad in 2009

PG: MCA (Computers) from GRAHAMBELL PG COLLEGE in 2013

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Ski	ill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
VIV	WARE	5	2016	3 Year(s) 3 Month(s)
1771		_	0040	F \//- \ O B ##-/- \

IIIL	5	ZU10	o year(s) o iviontin(s)
SCCM	2012	2016	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Windows 7 to Windows 8/10			
USMT,OSD MDT			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Telugu	Expert	✓	✓	✓
MARATHI				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: SC
Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.